ZACHARY BUTT

7329 7th Place SW, Seattle, WA 98106 (614)735-8664 | zacbutt8787@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ZacButt

GitHub.com/ZacButt ZacButt.GitHub.io

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

A hard-working, personable, friendly and responsible Full-Stack Developer who works well in a team environment. I have a strong understanding of Core programming concepts, and I'm well versed in many different languages such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, SQL and C#. I worked on two 2 week long live projects which can be viewed on my GitHub. The first Live Project was a Python project using Pycharm, Django and Azure Devops. I created a web app showing the NBA leader in assists and leader in points and seeing what correlation that has between how far a team makes it in the playoffs. My second live project was a C# using Visual studio code and Azure Devops. We created a movie database website, and I was in charge of the blog photos section. I also have completed a lot of other miscellaneous projects that can be viewed on my Github!

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Full-Stack Developer, Computer and Technology Basics, Version Control, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Pycharm, Django, Azure Devops, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, C#, and .Net Framework. Also very good with Social Media, Customer Service, Collaborative Leader, and a great ability to Self-teach.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Prosper IT Consulting - Portland, OR March 2023 to August 2023

- Software Developer Intern
- Full Stack Software Developer
- Trained in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, SQL, C# and .Net Framework

Town Studio, Denver, CO June 2020 to March 2023

- Fabric/Textile Specialist, Sampling Coordinator
- Improved inventory management, organized sample library
- Handled Client and Vendor Relationships, customer service, worked with outside sales team
- Increased Textile sales ~40% in the last 2 years

Dish Network, Denver, CO January 2020 - May 2020

• Customer Retention Sales Rep

Shaw Construction, Denver, CO June 2019 - December 2019

- General Laborer
- Helped build apartment complex
- Supervised temporary workers and directed their activities to meet goals/deadlines

Work experience while in college to help pay living expenses:

• Leasing Agent/Property Management of Family Rental Units 2014 - 2018

- Posted ads for leasing when apartments were available, scheduled appointments and leased apartments Cleaned/Painted interior and exterior of apartments in preparation for new tenants.
- Developed a punch list of things to repair and helped line up contractors when necessary.

Muetzel Plumbing, Pickerington, OH Summer of 2017

• Plumber's Helper- Hung pipe on new construction sites

Firehouse Subs, Pickerington, OH September 2016 - May 2017

• Team Leader, Trainer of new employees, Cook, Cashier

College Pro Painters, Pickerington, OH Summer of 2016

• Painted Residential Homes including pressure wash, trim, painting and clean-up

EDUCATION & TRAINING

The Tech Academy

- Software Developer Boot Camp
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, Java Script, SQL, Python, C#, .Net Framework
- Live projects completed in Python, and C#

Ohio University August 2015 - May 2019

• Completed 1 year Elementary Education and 3 years towards

Communications/Marketing degree

- Worked during college to help pay living expenses
- Volunteer work for Salvation Army

Pickerington HS North Graduated May 2015

- GPA 3.2, Honor Roll
- Varsity Football 1, 2, 3; Varsity Basketball 1
- Drama Club, Spring Musical, The Wedding Singer
- Volunteer: Project More, Outdoor Education
- Student Council President
- Student Section Leader